<Document>
  # SUBSECTION 3: Violations, Punishment and Varieties

  Violations of the Legal Mandate come in 4 Categories: Minor, Moderate, Major, and Capital.
  Each category comes with example violations and a recommended punishment type. Though
  the list is extensive, some possible violations do not have a listing in this document. It is up to
  the Warden and Head of Security of the station to deem the category of violations which are not
  described in examples. Some violations override each other, such as how Murder overrides
  Manslaughter.

  [italic]Note: If a total punishment time is above 20 minutes, the perpetrator is to be sent to permanent
  confinement (A.K.A Perma)[/italic]

  ##Minor
  - Upon a first offense, a warning should be issued.
  - If multiple minor violations occur, a maximum of 5 minutes per minor violation can be
  inflicted as a punishment.
  - If multiple occurrences of hooliganism occur, the perpetrator can be confined until
  they cease that behavior.


  ###Example Violations:

  Animal Cruelty
  - To inflict unnecessary suffering or harm on a non-sapient being with
  malicious intent. 
  - Here is an example of what is and what isn't animal cruelty:
    - To kill a creature such as Pun-Pun, Mort, or Ian that has not initiated any sort of attack upon you is Animal Cruelty.
    - To kill a monkey or kobold grown from a cube in the name of scientific advancement or supplying food to the station is NOT Animal Cruelty.
    - To do something such as skinning a monkey while it is alive is Animal Cruelty.
    - To defend yourself from an attacking animal is NOT Animal Cruelty.
    - To kill a pest such as a mouse, cockroach, snail, or pleebnar who has neither shown malicious intent nor has shown signs of sentience is NOT Animal Cruetly.
    - To kill a pet such as a mouse, hamster, squawkroach, mothroach, or other who has not shown neither malicious intent nor sentience is Animal Cruelty.
      - A pet must be declared prior to its death to publicly be a pet to the person committing Animal Cruetly for them to have properly committed Animal Cruelty.
      Animals such as Pun-Pun, Mort, Ian, and others who appear around the station are presumed to be a pet by default rather than requiring declaration.

  Petty Theft
  - To take non-vital or inexpensive property of another individual,
  organization, or common property, without consent.

  Possession of Controlled Substances
  - To make, hold, or abuse restricted chemicals without authorization.
  - This list includes substances such as poisons or narcotics.
  - Chemists are permitted to hold and use such chemicals while within the confines of
  the Medical Department. The Chief Medical Officer is permitted to hold and use such
  chemicals anywhere on the station. The Chief Medical Officer can as well write a permit
  for other members of the crew to hold and use such chemicals outside of the Medical Department.
  - Substances that are inherent to station functions or station design, such as ephedrine in
  stimulants used by Security Personnel, do not need a written permit.

  Vandalism
  - To intentionally defiance or superficially damage public or private property.
  - Trespass
  - To enter a non-secured area without permission.

  Hooliganism
  - To intentionally and maliciously engage in disruptive conduct.

  ##Moderate
  - The maximum sentence for a moderate violation is 10 minutes.
  - Depending on the situation, it may be ideal to issue a warning rather than detainment

  ###Example Violations

  Non-Compliance
  - To resist orders given by an authority. This extends to authorized
  searches.

  Breach of Arrest
  - To intentionally resist and flee arrest or detainment by an authorized staff.

  Possession of Restricted Items
  - To hold or use non-lethal items or objects that are restricted or illegal
  without a permit.
  - Permits must be signed and stamped by the Head of Security,
  Warden, or Captain.

  Destruction of Property
  - To maliciously damage or deface public or private property or equipment.

  Endangerment
  - To recklessly put yourself or others in danger through either direct action
  or failure to act.

  Assault/Battery
  - To threaten or to use physical force against someone without the intent to
  kill.
  - Examples of physical forces include but are not limited to:
    - Pushing, splashing water onto one, and other non-violent means of using physical force on someone.
    - Punching or hitting, such as with ones fist, an improvised weapon, or proper melee weapon.
    - Shooting, such as from laser, ballistic, or explosive weaponry.
    - Projected attacks, such as those from one's eyes, internal organs, or mind.


  ##Major

  - The maximum sentence for a major violation is 15 minutes
  - It is recommended to not use maximum sentences for those being compliant

  ###Example Violations

  Possession of Restricted Items of Menace
  - To hold or use lethal items, objects, or chemicals that are restricted or
  illegal without a permit.
  - Permits must be signed and stamped by the Head of Security,
  Warden, or Captain.
  - Weaponry that is inherent to department functions or station
  design, such as the proto-kinetic accelerator for salvage
  specialists or the shotgun for bartenders, do not require a written
  permit.

  Grand Theft
  - To take critical or unreplaceable property of another individual or
  organization without consent.

  Mass Destruction
  - To cause massive damage to an area or a major station system.

  Secure Trespass
  - To enter a secured area without permission.
  - Secure Areas include the following: EVA Storage, Tech Storage,
  Gravity Generator, Engineering Secure Storage, Vault, Armory,
  Command Zones, Security Zones.

  Manslaughter
  - To incidentally kill a member of the crew without intent.

  Rioting
  - To take part in a large group of personnel creating a collective display of
  disruptive or violative conduct.

  Kidnapping
  - To restrain, transport, control, or confine a non-hostile non-crewmember
  or a crewmember against that individual's will.

  Attempted Murder
  - To make an attempt to use physical force against someone with the clear
  intent to kill.

  Black Marketeering
  - To sell, distribute, or otherwise circulate Restricted Items or Restricted
  Items of Menace, as they are described in previous violations.

  Sabotage
  - To intentionally commit an act that, directly or indirectly, hinders the
  operations of the vessel or its part. As well to commit an act that modifies
  and/or damages technology or equipment one is not authorized to
  access.

  ##Capital

  Capital violations should usually lead to a death sentence, shift lasting detainment, or
  another variety of Capital Punishment.

  Capital Punishments can include the following options, or an option which is
  agreed on by the Captain, Head of Security, and the subject of the punishment.
  All Capital punishments are decided by the Captain or Acting Captain of the
  Station.

  - Permanent Confinement: To be held in the permanent brig for the entire
  duration of the shift. An individual subject to this punishment is required to
  be transported in cuffs to Central Command at the end of the shift. A
  permanent prisoner can not be deprived of anything covered by the
  section “Treatment of Prisoners.”
  - Execution: To terminate the life of an individual subjected to this
  punishment. A general announcement must be made stating who was
  executed and for what reason, outside of dire circumstance. The
  subjected individual is permitted to select the method of execution.
  Common methods include a firing line, lethal injection, high voltage
  electricity, or a method devised by the subject. The remains of the subject
  are to be cremated or stored in the morgue.
  - Decorporealization: To strip the subject of the punishment’s mind from
  their body into a more restrictive form. Placing a subject into a borg vessel
  is the most common form of this punishment.
  - Exile: To transport the subject of this punishment to an area far away
  from the station. This area can be a nearby asteroid, a broken down
  wreck, lavaland, or an area deemed to be adequate by the Captain or
  Head of Security. The subject must be provided with the bare necessities
  for temporary survival, such as the contents of an emergency supplies
  box, and at minimum one tank and a suit capable of survival in the
  vacuum of space if
  - Alternate Method: An alternate capital punishment can be proposed by
  the Captain of the station. This punishment must be agreed upon by the
  Captain, the Head of Security, and the Warden of the station.


  ###Example Violations

  Breach of Custody
  - To break out of a cell or custody with the intention of escaping.

  Murder
  - To kill a sapient being with malicious intent.

  Prevention of Revival
  - To render a body unable to be resurrected.

  Sedition
  - To act to overthrow an established Chain of Command without legitimate
  cause.

  Terrorism
  - To commit an act or take hostages with reckless indifference to crew life
  in order to provoke a state of terror in, intimidate, or otherwise compel an
  entity to act or abstain from acting.

  Grand Sabotage
  - To intentionally commit an act that, directly or indirectly, renders a vessel
  in part inhabitable or inoperable. To commit and act that causes
  irreversible damage to Secure Areas.
</Document>
